Joshua Jarvis

Software Engineer

Contact

joshuajarviso711@gmail.com (385)254-1876 linkedin.com/in/jsivraj github.com/ixonstater

Education

Utah Valley University

GPA: 3.7

BASc

Software Development

Relevant Coursework

Web Development Data Structures Numerical Analysis Mobile Device Programming

Applicable Skills

MySql | MariaDB | MongoDB
Cassandra | Flutter | Angular
React Native | Android
Android Studio | Node | NPM
Apache | Nginx | Flask
Javascript / Typescript | Dart
Python | PHP | C++ | Java
HTML5 | CSS3 | Git | Bash
Linux | Docker | AWS
Team City | Gitlab CI
Azure DevOps | Digital Ocean

References

Julie Lee

Software Developer - Motivosity (801) 669-4770

Aarron Rasmussen

Software Developer - Anchor 6 (801) 360-2263

About Me

I am a Software Engineer with 4 years of professional experience primarily in enterprise application development. I live in north-eastern Wisconsin with my wife and two kids. I enjoy gardening, carpentry and video game development in my spare time. I'm passionate about large-scale data storage, application portability and the effects of AI on the software engineering landscape.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer II

Verisk, Lehi UT, Aug 2022 - Present

- Re-launched an existing codebase for a new market. Deployment included significant AWS work.
- Developed website features that would integrate with an Android video-collaboration application.
- Angular, Typescript, Java, Postgres, MongoDB, SQS, SNS, S3, Snowflake, Splunk
- Helped scale the starting team of three developers to a international team of 20+ including contractors. Helped interview candidates and make hiring decisions.

Completing Bachelors Degree

UVU, Orem UT, May 2021 - August 2022

Software Engineer II

ABGRM, Murray UT, Oct 2019 - May 2021

- Maintained and developed a cross-platform mobile application using Ionic and Angular.
- Maintained and refactored large quantities of undocumented code. Reading and understanding code with little or no frame of reference.
- Android, Javascript CSS, HTML, NPM, Angular, Python, PHP, Docker, Ubuntu, SAML
- Build a Python task scheduler to execute re-balance trades by connecting to an oracle database, assembling an XML instruction string, and calling a system executable.

Misc. Consulting

- Built and deployed a mobile game to the Google Play store to get a feel for Google ad campaigns.
- Collaborated with two other devs on a Flutter / Android app for a startup company that sold automotive information videos to mechanic shops.